Abraham: 'Hacking' is the process of
compromising and gaining unauthorised
access to a computer system or systems,
whole networks or digital devices and
taking control and inserting malware.
This can be motivated by financial
gain, protest, information
gathering or just for the challenge!
Hackers can be from a range of backgrounds
and have different motives and may
include self-taught 'kids' or rogue IT
programmers and professionals skilled at
modifying computer hardware and software.
Hacking can involve technical skills
which can create “malvertising” or
malicious advertising which uses online
advertising to spread and install malware.
Hackers inject infected ads into
legitimate advertising networks that
display ads on trusted websites.
But hackers also use psychology to
trick users into clicking on malicious
attachments or providing personal
data also known as social engineering.
Hacking is an umbrella term which
covers a range of different cyber
attacks and has evolved from a lone
individual working from their bedroom
to a widely established criminal
enterprise with turnkey hacking tools
available to those with lesser skills.
So, what motivates hackers
to commit their crimes.
It may be financial gain such as
the theft of credit card details or
defrauding individuals and banks.
Also holding companies to ransom.
It may be for gaining a reputation in
the hacker subculture by pulling off
hacks on sites and leaving their 'marks'
It may be for corporate espionage
where one company may hack another
to steal their information and gain a
marketplace advantage or individuals
will offer their services for sale.
It may be state sponsored with
nations stealing business, military
or national intelligence secrets and
trying to destabilise other nations.
It may also involve Hacker Activists
or Hacktivists who are politically
or socially motivated and may wish to
raise public awareness and focus public
attention on something or someone.
It’s important to remember that
an individual or a business may
not always be the end target.
You may even think why would
anyone want to hack me?
But they may be a step along the way.
An individual or business may be hacked
because of the established connections
they have to a higher value target.